Guide to the Trade catalogs collection.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- J
  - Jones, Charles (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai J7145; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1781)
    Hardware, china, crockery, and glass
  - Jones, F. Noble (London, England), undated; Uai J712; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1778)
    Gloves and fans
  - Jones, Faulkner and Company (Utica, N.Y.), undated; Uai J715; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1782)
    Apparatus for cheese factories and creameries
  - Jones, W. and S. (London, England), 1837–1851; Uai J714; 2 volumes (Box 151, Folder 1779-1780)
    Optical, mathematical and philosophical instruments
  - Jordan, O. F., Company (East Chicago, Ind.), 1925; Uai +J765; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1786)
    Jordan spreader
  - Joyce-Cridland Company (Dayton, Ohio), 1912; Uai J851; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1787)
    Lifting jacks
  - Judd Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1871–1872; Uai J885; 4 volumes (Box 151, Folder 1788-1790)
  - Judd, H. L. (New Haven, Conn.), 1871–1873; Uai +J883; 6 volumes (Box 155, Folder 1802-1804)
    Upholsterers' and builders' hardware
  - Judd, H. L. and Company, Judd, H. L., Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1881–1885; Uai +J884; 5 volumes (Box 156, Folder 1805-1808)
    Ornamental hardware
  - Judd, M. and A. D. (New Haven, Conn.), 1868; Uai J886; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1791)
    Sash fasteners, door latches, etc.
  - Judge Publishing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1893; 1 volume (Box 399, Folder 4318)
  - Judkins, Charles T. (London, England), 1854; Uai J91; 1 volume (Box 151, Folder 1792)
    Gas regulator, sewing machine
  - Julien Electric Company (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai +J94; 2 volumes (Box 151, Folder 1793)
  - Julien, Alexis A. (New York, N.Y.), 1878; Uai J944; 2 volumes (Box 151, Folder 1794)
    Lithologists' requisites, etc.
- K
  - Kaehler, Max, and Martini (Berlin, Germany), 1894–1898; Uai +K117; 4 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1809-1810)
    Chemical, electrochemical, and bacteriological apparatus
  - Kaffee Hag Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1941; Uai K119; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1811)
    Coffee
  - Kahlbaum, C. A. F. (Berlin, Germany), 1874–1913; Uai +K121; 38 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1812-1825)
  - Kahler, Dr. P., and Sons (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai K122; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1826)
    Boots and shoes
  - Kalamazoo Loose Leaf Binder Company (Kalamazoo, Mich.), 1912; Uai K1242; 2 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1827)
    Loose leaf accounting systems and supplies
  - Kalamazoo Steel Goods Company (Kalamazoo, Mich.), 1923; Uai K1244; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1828)
    Steel furniture and specialties
  - Kalamazoo Stove Company (Kalamazoo, Mich.), 1937; Uai +K1246; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1829)
    Heaters, ranges, and furnaces
  - Kalker Werkzeugmaschinen-Fabrik (Kalk, Germany), 1887–1892; Uai +K126; 3 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1830)
    Hydraulic machinery, etc.
  - Kalle and Company, Inc. (Biebrich on Rhine, Germany), 1923; Uai K128; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1831)
    Dyestuffs
  - Karol, B., and Sons Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1929; Uai +K146; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1832)
    Plumbing and heating supplies
  - Keating Wheel Company (Middletown, Conn.), 1899; Uai K22; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1833)
  - Kedian and Brothers (New York, N.Y.), 1885; Uai K237; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1834)
    Furnaces, heaters, ranges, etc.
  - Keeley Stove Company (Columbia, Pa.), 1911–1912; Uai K246; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1835)
    Stoves, furnaces, and ranges
  - Keiser and Schmidt (Berlin, Germany), 1870–1893; Uai +K268; 3 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1837-1838)
    Electrical apparatus, etc.
  - Keiser, James R. (New York, N.Y.), 1902; Uai K267; 2 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1836)
    Cravats, belts, and stocks
  - Keith, Geo. E. Company (Campello, Mass.), 1902; Uai K269; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1839)
    "Walk-over" shoes
  - Kelley, Edward G. (New York, N.Y.), 1860; Uai K287; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1840)
    Chemicals, Chemical and philosophical apparatus
  - Kelley, Maus and Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1882; Uai K2883; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1842)
  - Kelley-Koett Manufacturing Company (Covington, Ky.), 1912–1915; Uai +K288; 9 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1841)
    X-ray apparatus, etc.
  - Kellogg Manufacturing Company (Rochester, N.Y.), undated; Uai K291; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1844)
    Automobile parts
  - Kellogg, Spencer, and Sons, Inc. (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1940; Uai K29; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1843)
    Laboratory letters
  - Kelly Reamer Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1915; Uai K298; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1846)
    Adjustable reamers
  - Kelly, Thos., and Brothers (Chicago, Ill.), 1898; Uai +K297; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1845)
  - Kelly-Springfield Tire Company (New York, N.Y.), 1923; Uai K2982; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1847)
  - Kelsey Heating Company (Syracuse, N.Y.), 1905; Uai K2986; 2 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1848)
    Warm air generators
  - Keltner Manufacturing Company (Delaware, Ohio), 1932; Uai K299; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1849)
    Church and lodge furniture
  - Kelvinator Corporation (Detroit, Mich.), 1935; Uai +K31; 3 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1850)
  - Kemp and Burpee Manufacturing Company (Syracuse, N.Y.), 1882; Uai K32; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1851)
    Manure spreader
  - Kendrick and Davis (Lebanon, N.H.), 1900; Uai K347; 2 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1852)
    Motors and fans, etc.
  - Kennebec Boat and Canoe Company (Waterville, Me.), 1918; Uai K368; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1853)
    Boats and canoes
  - Kennedy-Van Saun Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1917–1930; Uai +K386; 7 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1854-1857)
    Mining, crushing, and cement-making machinery, etc.
  - Kenrick, A., and Sons (West Bomwich, England), 1876–1880; Uai K411; 2 volumes (Box 161, Folder 1992-1993)
    Kitchen utensils, hardware, etc.
  - Kent, Edward N. (New York, N.Y.), 1848–1863; Uai K414; 6 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1858-1860)
    Chemicals and chemical apparatus
  - Kentucky Alcohol Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1928; Uai +K419; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1861)
    Alcohol
  - Kenworthy, Charles F., Inc. (Waterbury, Conn.), undated; Uai +K421; 3 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1862)
  - Kermel Apparatus Company (Cambridge, Mass.), undated; Uai K458; 2 volumes (Box 158, Folder 1863)
    Switchboard instruments, Voltmeters, Ammeters, etc.
  - Kern Burner Company (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai +K459; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1864)
    Kern burner
  - Ketcham, E., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1877; Uai K491; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1865)
    Tin wares, etc.
  - Ketchum, Landon (South Norwalk, Conn.), 1884; Uai K492; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1866)
    Challenge water heater
  - Keuffel and Esser Company (New York, N.Y.), Uai K516
    Drawing materials, Surveying instruments, etc.
    - 1876–1887, 7 volumes (Box 162, Folder 1994-1998)
    - 1887–1937, 12 volumes (Box 163, Folder 1999-2003)
  - Kewaunee Manufacturing Company (Kewaunee, Wis.), 1916; Uai K5195; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1867)
    Laboratory furniture
  - Keyless Lock Company (Chicago, Ill., etc.), 1893–1896; Uai +K521; 9 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1868-1869)
    "Craig" keyless locks
  - Keystone Bridge Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1874; Uai +K522; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1870)
    Bridges, etc.
  - Keystone View Company (Meadville, Pa.), 1905; Uai K523; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1871)
    Stereographs and slides
  - Kieley and Mueller (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1910; Uai K543; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1872)
    Steam, water, and air specialties
  - Kilborn and Bishop Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1915; Uai K5512; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1874)
    Drop forgings and forged hardware
  - Kilborn, Holloway (New Haven, Conn.), 1940; Uai +K551; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1873)
    "Rubberule"
  - Kilbourne and Jacobs Manufacturing Company (Columbus, Ohio), 1914–1919; Uai K552; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1875)
    Trucks, etc.
  - Kimberly-Clark Corporation (Neenah, Wis.), 1936; Uai K565; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1876)
  - Kimble Glass Company (Vineland, N.J.), 1934–1936; Uai +K568; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1877)
    Laboratory glassware, etc.
  - Kinetor Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1930; Uai +K579; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1878)
    Machine tool
  - King, Geo. F., and Merrill (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai K582; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1879)
    School supplies, etc.
  - King, J. B., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1891–1892; Uai +K583; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1880)
    Cement, plaster, etc.
  - King, J. D. (Cottage City, Mass., etc.), undated; Uai K584; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1881)
    Cement finishes, Microscopes, etc.
  - Kingsbury Machine Works (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1931–1932; Uai +K611; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1882)
    Bearings
  - Kinnear Manufacturing Company (Columbus, Ohio), 1905; Uai +K624; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1884)
    Steel rolling doors, shutters, and partitions
  - Kinnear and Gager Company (Columbus, Ohio), 1899; Uai +K623; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1883)
    Steel interior decorations
  - Kinney Manufacturing Company (Boston, Mass.), 1940; Uai +K6245; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1885)
    Liquid and vacuum pumps
  - Kipe Offset Process Company (Culpeper, Va.), 1943; Uai K628; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1886)
    Rochester ropes
  - Kirk Manufacturing Company (Toledo, Ohio), 1899–1902; Uai K634; 2 volumes (Box 393)
    "Yale" bicycles
  - Kirk, H. B., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1888; Uai K632; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1887)
    Wine and spirits
  - Kirk, Samuel, and Son, Inc. (Baltimore, Md.), 1938; Uai K633; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1888)
    Sterling silverware
  - Kirstein, E., Sons Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1911; Uai +K639; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1889)
    "Shur-on" optical products
  - Kitching, Jno. B. (New York, N.Y.), 1860; Uai K648; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1890)
    Ericsson's caloric engine
  - Kitchoukis, Athanase (Constantiople, Turkey), 1921; Uai K649; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1891)
    Stamps, etc.
  - Klad-eeze (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1940; Uai +K661; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1892)
    Children's clothing
  - Klein, D., and Brother (Philadelphia, Pa.), undated; Uai K672; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1893)
    Uniforms, etc.
  - Kleine, Charles B. (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai K673; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1894)
    Scientific instruments, etc.
  - Kleine, Lewis T. (Alpena, Mich.), 1922; Uai K680; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1895)
    Wood turning machinery
  - Klöckner-Werke A.-G., Georgs-Marien-Hütte (Osnabrück, Germany), 1932; Uai K692; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1896)
    Iron pile-planking
  - Knecht Brothers (Cincinnati, Ohio), undated; Uai K731; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1897)
    Drill press
  - Knickerbocker Silver Company (Port Jervis, N.Y.), 1911; Uai +K741; 1 volume (Box 167)
    Silverware
  - Knight Manufacturing Company (Canton, Ohio), undated; Uai +K747; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1899)
  - Knight and Thomas (Boston, Mass.), 1897–1903; Uai +K746; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1898)
    "Underwriters' " fire extinguishers
  - Knoll and Company (London, England, New York, N.Y., etc.), 1913; Uai K755; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1900)
  - Knott, L. E., Apparatus Company (Boston, Mass.), Uai +K759
    Physical, chemical, and scientific instruments, etc.
    - 1901–1912, 3 volumes (Box 164, Folder 2004-2005)
    - 1912–1921, 2 volumes (Box 165, Folder 2006-2007)
  - Knowles Steam Pump Works (New York, N.Y., Boston, Mass.), 1882; Uai +K764; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1901)
    Independent condensing apparatus
  - Knox (New York, N.Y.), 1901; Uai K776; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1902)
  - Knox Motors Company (Springfield, Mass.), 1915; Uai +K777; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1903)
  - Kny-Scheerer Company (New York, N.Y.), 1907–1910; Uai +K788; 2 volumes (Box 166, Folder 2008-2009)
    Laboratory supplies and anatomical models
  - Kny-Scheerer Corporation of America (New York, N.Y.), 1925; Uai K789; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1904)
    Museum and naturalists' supplies
  - Koela Producer-Gas Plant Company (London, England), 1934; Uai K817; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1906)
    Charcoal fuel
  - Koenig, E. G. (Newark, N.J.), undated; Uai +K818; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1908)
  - Kohl, Max (Chemnitz, Germany), 1896–1899; Uai +K822; 14 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1913-1923)
    Physical and electrical instruments
  - Kohlbusch, Herman (New York, N.Y.), 1892–1902; Uai K823; 2 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1924)
  - Kohler Company (Kohler, Wis.), 1925–1926; Uai +K824; 3 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1925-1926)
    Enameled plumbing ware
  - Kohn, Alois, and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1907; Uai K826; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1927)
    Gold chains
  - Kohn, Jacob and Josef (Vienna, Austria), undated; Uai +K827; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1928)
  - Koken Barbers' Supply Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1910; Uai +K829; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1929)
    Barbers' furniture and supplies
  - Kollsman Instrument Company (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1934; Uai +K834; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1930)
    Aircraft instruments
  - Kopf, C. W., Company (Boston, Mass.), 1891; Uai +K838; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1931)
    Concentrated pea soup
  - Koppers Company, Inc. (Baltimore, Md.), 1945; Uai +K8395; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1932)
    Industrial equipment
  - Korndörfer, Filibert (New York, N.Y.), 1939; Uai K842; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1933)
    Pineol pocket inhaler
  - Kozy Camera Company (Boston, Mass.), 1900–1902; Uai K849; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1934)
    Cameras and photographic supplies
  - Kraft Cheese Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1940; Uai K855; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1935)
    Cheese, etc.
  - Krantz, H. Manufacturing Company (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1914; Uai K863; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1936)
    Straight line electrical panels
  - Krause, Karl (Leipzig, Germany), 1887–1913; Uai +K868; 7 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1937-1938)
    Paper cutting machines, etc.
  - Krauss, E., and Company (Berlin, Germany), undated; Uai K869; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1939)
  - Kreiger, Oscar, G.m.b.H. (Dresden, Germany), 1932; Uai +K893; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1940)
    Wheelbarrows, trucks, etc.
  - Krupp. Fried., Germaniawerft A. G. (Kiel-Gaarden, Germany), 1926; Uai K944; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1943)
  - Krüss, A. (Hamburg, Germany), 1890–1895; Uai K936; 5 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1941-1942)
    Optical instruments, Photographic apparatus, etc.
  - Kurka, R. (Frankfort, Germany), 1900; Uai +K965; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1944)
    Kurka's stone-filter system
  - Kwikprint Company, Inc. (Chicago, Ill.), 1941; Uai +K979; 5 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1945)
    "Kwikprint" gold stamping machines and supplies
  - Köhler, Fritz (Leipzig, Germany), 1905; Uai K816; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1905)
    Physics and chemistry apparatus
  - König, Dr. Heinr., and Company (Leipzig-Plagwitz, Germany), 1907; Uai K8175; 1 volume (Box 159, Folder 1907)
  - Kœnig, Rudolph (Paris, France), 1859–1889; Uai K8185; 5 volumes (Box 159, Folder 1909-1912)
    Acoustical apparatus
- L
  - La France Textile Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1922; Uai L134; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1952)
    Tapestries
  - LaMotte Chemical Products Company (Baltimore, Md.), 1924–1944; Uai L19; 3 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1964)
    Chemicals and chemical apparatus, etc.
  - Laboratoire d'Hypoderme de Paris (Paris, France), 1939; Uai L113; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1946)
  - Lachenal, J., Favrem L., et Cie (Paris, France), 1878; Uai L116; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1947)
    Stereoscopic views, photographs, etc.
  - Lackawanna Steel Company (Buffalo, N.Y.), Uai +L118
    Steel sheet piling
    - 1915, 2 volumes (Box 175)
    - 1899, 1 volume (Box 176)
  - Lackner, Carl (Berlin, Germany), 1882–1883; Uai L119; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1948)
    Greenhouse plants, roses, etc.
  - Ladd, William (London, England), 1858–1872; Uai L121; 3 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1949)
    Optical, mathematical, and philosophical instruments
  - Ladew, Edw. R., Company, Inc. (Glen Cove, N.Y.), 1918–1923; Uai +L124; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1950)
  - Laflin and Rand Powder Company (New York, N.Y.), 1886; Uai L133; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1951)
    Gunpowder and high explosives
  - Lagonda Manufacturing Company (Springfield, Ohio), 1917; Uai +L137; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1953)
    Automatic cut-off valves
  - Laidlaw-Dunn-Gordon Company (Cincinnati, Ohio), undated; Uai L141; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1954)
  - Lake Erie Iron Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1884; Uai L147; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1955)
    Steel and iron forgings
  - Lakeside Press Galleries, 1942; Uai +L1475; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1956)
    Photography
  - Lakin, J. A., and Company (Westfield, Mass.), 1885; Uai L148; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1957)
    Time draft for furnaces and heaters
  - Lalance and Grosjean Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1874–1877; Uai L151; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1958-1959)
    Nickel and silver-plated ware
  - Lally Column Companies (Cambridge, Mass.), 1926; Uai L157; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1960)
    Lally columns
  - Lamb Manufacturing Company (Chicopee Falls, Mass.), 1895–1899; Uai L166; 3 volumes (Box 394)
    "Spalding" bicycles
  - Lamb, J. and R. (New York, N.Y.), 1872–1881; Uai L165; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1961)
    Church furnishings, etc.
  - Lambert Brothers (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai L172; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1962)
    Medals, class pins, and class rings
  - Lambert Pharmacal Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1935; Uai +L175; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1963)
    Listerine antiseptic
  - Lamson Consolidated Store Service Company (Boston, Mass.), 1898–1920; Uai +L216; 13 volumes (Box 177)
    Pneumatic tube service and conveyors, etc.
  - Landers, Frary, and Clark (New Britain, Conn.), 1914; Uai +L233; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1965)
    Household electrical appliances, etc.
  - Landis Brothers (Waynesboro, Pa.), 1893–1895; Uai +L2356; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1967)
    Tool builders, grinding machines, etc.
  - Landis Machine Company (Waynesboro, Pa.), 1917; Uai +L2359; 3 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1968)
    Threading machines
  - Landis, Israel L. (Lancaster, Pa.), 1873; Uai L2352; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1966)
    Fences and gates
  - Lane, J. W., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1857; Uai L241; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1969)
    Gold's patent steam heating apparatus
  - Lane, M. R., and Sons (Ardmore, Pa.), 1930; Uai +L242; 3 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1970)
    Golf and tennis equipment, etc.
  - Langbein-Kaufman Radio Company (New Haven, Conn.), undated; Uai L258; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1971)
    Elkay radios
  - Langdon Mitre Box Company (Millers Falls, Mass.), 1877; Uai +L259; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1972)
    Langdon adjustable mitre box
  - Lansing Wheelbarrow Company (Lansing, Mich.), undated; Uai L291; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1973)
    Sleigh runners, etc.
  - Lasch, C. L., and Company (Leipzig-Reudnitz, Germany), undated; Uai +L332; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1974)
  - Latham, E. B., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1912–1913; Uai L346; 3 volumes (Box 171, Folder 2152-2153)
  - Lathrop, J. W., and Company (Mystic, Conn.), 1922; Uai L348; 2 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1975)
    Gasoline and kerosene engines
  - Laurent, Léon (Paris, France), 1877–1882; Uai L373; 7 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1976)
    Mirrors and projection apparatus, etc.
  - Laurie, Thomas (London, England), undated; Uai L375; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1977)
    Scientific and technical apparatus
  - Lavigne and Scott Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1896; Uai +L39; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1978)
    Bicycle equipment, hardware specialties, yacht cannon, etc.
  - Lawler Regulating Company (New York, N.Y.), 1913; Uai L423; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1979)
    Thermostatic steam and hot water temperature regulating devices
  - Lawrence Machine Company (Lawrence, Mass.), 1897; Uai L437; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1982)
    Centrifugal pumps
  - Lawrence, Bradley and Pardee (New Haven, Conn.), 1862; Uai L436; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1981)
    Carriages, sleighs, etc.
  - Lawrence, C. A. (Beverly, Mass.), 1875; Uai +L435; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1980)
    Pottery, etc.
  - Lawson Improved Dumping Boat and Car Company (New York, N.Y.), 1901; Uai L444; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1983)
    Instantaneous unloader for cars and boats
  - Lawson Manufacturing Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1930; Uai +L445; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1984)
    "Lawson" coil heaters
  - Lay, Clarke and Company (Santa Rosa, Calif.), 1892; Uai L451; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1985)
  - Layton, C. and E. (London, England), 1889; Uai L455; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1986)
    Calculating machine
  - Le Bland, R. K., Machine Tool Company (Cincinnati, Ohio), 1912–1931; Uai L492; 3 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1988)
    Lathes, combination miller, etc.
  - Le Bosquet Brothers (Boston, Mass.), 1874; Uai L493; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1989)
    Nichols wrought-iron furnace
  - Le Valley Vitae Carbon Brush Company (New York, N.Y.), 1925; Uai L575; 2 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2035)
    Carbon brushes
  - League of American Wheelmen (Boston, Mass., etc.), 1884–1893; 4 volumes (Box 399, Folder 4319)
  - Lebault, P., et Cie (Paris, France), 1892; Uai L491; 1 volume (Box 160, Folder 1987)
    Vino de Bugeaud tonic
  - Lederle Antitoxin Laboratories (New York, N.Y.), 1913–1939; Uai +L498; 5 volumes (Box 160, Folder 1990-1991)
    Vaccines, etc.
  - Lee Tire and Rubber Company (Conshohocken, Pa.), 1911; Uai L516; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2014)
  - Lee and Zimmerman (Rochester, N.Y.), undated; Uai L513; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2013)
    Heat regulator
  - Lee, Charles E. (Rochester, N.Y.), 1887; Uai L511; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2010)
    Temperature regulator
  - Lee, Harry C., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1912; Uai L512; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2011)
    Golf and tennis equipment
  - Lee, Wilson H., Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1914–1916; Uai +L5126; 3 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2012)
    Monotype machines, etc.
  - Leedom, Thomas L. (Bristol, Pa.), 1890; Uai +L5165; 1 volume (Box 178)
    Carpets and rugs
  - Leeds and Northrup Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1906–1944; Uai +L517; 16 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2015-2017)
    Heat-treating furnaces, telemeters, etc.
  - Leffel, James, and Company (Springfield, Ohio), 1870; Uai +L521; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2018)
    Double turbine water wheel
  - Leggett, Francis H., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1884; Uai +L524; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2019)
    Groceries, etc.
  - Lehn and Fink (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai L528; 2 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2020)
    Medicinal products, etc.
  - Leibig's Extract of Meat Company (London, England), 1886; Uai L621; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2054)
    Stockpots, etc.
  - Leiman Brothers (New York, N.Y.), 1911; Uai L533; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2021)
    Machinery for jewelers, silversmiths, and metal workers
  - Leitz, E., Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1926–1935; Uai +L537; 8 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2022-2023)
    Microscopes, cameras, etc.
  - Leitz, Ernst (New York, N.Y., Wetzlar, Germany), 1894; Uai L538; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2024)
    Microscopes and accessory apparatus
  - Lenoir, G. A. (Vienna, Austria), undated; Uai L548; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2025)
    Scientific apparatus, etc.
  - Leonard Valve Company (Providence, R.I.), 1937; Uai +L5524; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2027)
    Thermostatic water mixing valves
  - Leonard, E., and Sons (London, Ontario, Canada), 1891; Uai +L552; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2026)
    Leonard-Tangye engine
  - Leonhardi, Aug. (Dresden, Germany), 1911–1923; Uai +L553; 2 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2028)
    Inks, etc.
  - Leppin and Masche (Berlin, Germany), 1885; Uai +L558; 4 volumes (Box 168, Folder 2029-2032)
  - Lerebours et Secretan (Paris, France), 1845–1853; Uai +L561; 3 volumes (Box 172, Folder 2154-2156)
    Optical, physical, and chemical instruments, etc.
  - Leroy, L., et Cie (Paris, France), 1904; Uai L562; 1 volume (Box 168, Folder 2033)
    Watches and clocks